（鮮血(せんけつ)）やあ みんな
Hey there, everyone!
Thanks for watching
KILL la KILL every week!
いつも「キルラキル」を
見てくれて ありがとう
I'm Godrobe Senketsu,
私の名は神衣(かむい)鮮血
a living sailor uniform that loves ironing—
or rather, being ironed.
アイロンがけ… いや
アイロンがけられが大好きな—
生きたセーラー服だ
Now, here's something that I'm sure
you've all been expecting for quite some time.
さあ そろそろくるんじゃないかと
みんなが思っていた—
It's time for a recap episode!
あの総集編の始まりだ
RECAP
Matoi Ryuuko, a girl looking for the woman
with the Sword Scissor who killed her father,
父の敵 片太刀バサミの女を捜す
纏流子(まといりゅうこ)は—
KILLED HER FATHER
runs into Kiryuuin Satsuki,
the student council president at Honnouji Academy.
本能字(ほんのうじ)学園でその鍵を握る生徒会長
鬼龍院皐月(きりゅういんさつき)に巡り合う
KIRYUUIN SATSUKI
Satsuki was planning to take over all of the nation's
schools using Ultima Uniforms fitted with Life Fibers
皐月は人間の特殊能力を
引き出す—
生命戦維(せんい)を織り込んだ
極(ごく)制服をもって—
that awakened special powers within humans,
全国学園支配を企てていた
but Ryuuko gained the power to oppose Satsuki
and her cronies by meeting me, Godrobe Senketsu.
だが流子は私 神衣鮮血と
出会うことで—
GODROBE SENKETSU
皐月たちと戦う力を手に入れた
The Boxing Club, the Tennis Club,
the traps devised by the Disciplinary Committee,
ボクシング部 テニス部
風紀部 トラップ開発部 園芸部
the Gardening Club, the Rakugo Club,
the 100 Poets Club, the Knife Throwing Club,
落語部 百人一首部 投げナイフ部
南京玉すだれ部 その他
and so on and so forth.
After the defeat of all these clubs
came the Naturals Election.
有象無象の部活を倒した末
行われた壊惨総戦挙(かいさんそうせんきょ)
The time had come to
take on the Four Devas.
ついに本能字四天王との
戦いが始まった
Against all odds, Ryuuko defeated
Gamagoori Ira, Inumuta Houka, and Jakuzure Nonon,
苦戦しながらも蟇郡苛(がまごおりいら) 犬牟田宝火(いぬむたほうか)
蛇崩乃音(じゃくずれののん)を倒した流子の前に—
only to be suddenly faced
by a girl called Harime Nui.
突然現れる針目縫(はりめぬい)という少女
She was the woman with the Sword Scissor
that Ryuuko was looking for.
彼女こそ流子の父 纏一身(いっしん)を殺した
片太刀バサミの女だったのだ
Then came the appearance of Satsuki's mother,
the head of the Kiryuuin conglomerate, Kiryuuin Ragyou.
さらに鬼龍院財閥の総帥
皐月の母親 鬼龍院羅暁(らぎょう)の登場
To complete her takeover
of schools across the country,
皐月は全国学園支配の
総仕上げとして—
Satsuki ordered a Battlefield Trip
to the Big Three Kansai-area cities.
関西圏三都制圧
襲学(しゅうがく)旅行を実行する
But schools weren't the
only thing she was after.
その狙いは学園だけでなく
鬼龍院一族に対抗する—
She also wanted to take out Nudist Beach, the anti-uniform
organization that opposed the Kiryuuin family.
反制服組織ヌーディスト･ビーチを
たたくことだった
In order to put my pieces back together,
Ryuuko headed to Kansai too.
バラバラにされた私を元に戻すため
流子も関西に向かう
In the city of wealth, Osaka,
Ryuuko and Satsuki engaged in mortal combat.
銭の街 大阪で繰り広げられる
流子と皐月の死闘
And today, the secret behind the
Life Fibers will finally be revealed!
そして今日 ついに生命戦維の
謎が明かされるのだ
Fret not, all of you that were
disappointed to hear this was a recap.
“総集編”と聞いて
がっかりした諸君 安心したまえ
Breakneck pacing is a
hallmark of KILL la KILL.
展開の早いのが「キルラキル」
総集編もアバンで終わる
Even the recap episode
only lasts as long as an intro!
The actual story continues now!
ここからは本編の始まりだ！
The tides of war will change drastically!
（皐月）だが戦局は大きく動く
Ignorant as you are,
何も知らぬお前では絶対に勝てない
you stand no chance of victory!
That's exactly why I keep asking
you to tell me, dammit!
（流子）だから いろいろ教えろ
つってんだろうが！
All you've ever done is beat around
the bush! Get off your high horse!
さんざん思わせぶり言ってる
ヤツが偉そうにしやがって
Screw you, Ms. Bigmouth Eyebrows!
このフトマユ への字口(ぐち)が〜！
EPISODE 16
THE GIRL CAN'T HELP IT
unmei no ito wo tachikitta sono saki ni
It all begins when we sever the threads of fate
senobi shiteitanda
I was trying to be someone I'm not
kutsuzure darake no
In a cramped world
semai sekai de
With no breathing room
runway wo aruku
As I walked down my runway
egao no uragawa
I thought I'd concealed it
kakushita tsumori de
Behind the smile that masked my face
dakedo itsumo kimi ni wa
But it doesn't work on you
minukarete shimatte ite
You always see through my facade
konna no wa hajimete de
Nobody's ever unraveled me like this before
tomadou kedo
I don't know what to do
hoka no dare ni mo kikonasenai
Nobody else can pull these outfits off
nandaka wakannai
A somewhat ambiguous fever
atsusa ga mune wo kogasu kara
Threatens to burn our hearts away
unmei no ito taguriyoseta sono saki ni
It all begins once we rein in the threads of fate
ima atarashii yoake ga kuru
A new day will dawn for us
omoi wa kitto hitotsu
We must be one in spirit
ハァ… うっ ハァ
Milady!
（揃(そろい)）お嬢様！
（揃）糸郎(しろう)！
（伊織(いおり)）はい！
Shirou!
Right away!
It's a tranquilizing coagulant.
（揃）鎮静凝固剤です
Please take this opportunity
to change out of your Godrobe.
今のうちにお脱ぎください
すまない
Thanks.
（皐月）うっ ハァ…
Your fights seem to be taking a
greater toll on your body than before.
（揃）
以前より疲労度が上がっています
It's too risky to activate Life Fiber Override
for as long as you have been.
長時間の人衣(じんい)圧倒状態は
危険でございます
I'm aware of the risk.
（皐月）危険は承知の上だ
But so long as Matoi
continues to wear her Godrobe,
だが 纏が神衣を着ている以上—
ヤツと戦うには純潔を着るしかない
I have no choice but to
don Junketsu to fight her.
（揃）
お言葉どおりでございます お嬢様
It is as you say, Milady.
（伊織）いいんですか？ おじさん
Are you sure, Uncle?
Shirou.
（揃）糸郎 お前も私の甥(おい)なら
そろそろ理解しなさい
As my nephew,
it is about time you realized
皐月お嬢様は—
that once Lady Satsuki has her heart
set on something, she never backs down.
一度お決めになったことは
絶対にお譲りにならない
The only thing we can do is
support her and her decisions.
我々にできるのは
そのサポートだけだ
Soroi, Iori.
揃 伊織
お前たちには苦労をかける
I've made many
selfish demands of you two.
But please allow me
to do so for just a little longer.
が… もうしばらくは
わがままを許してくれ
（受信音）
（スピーカー:縫）ふう〜ん
Oh?
皐月様 結構無理してたんだ
So you were pushing yourself,
Lady Satsuki?
Who are you?!
（伊織）誰だ？
...That voice...
Is that you, Harime?
（スピーカー:皐月）針目か？
（縫）はい そのとおり
Sure is!
The Grand Couturier?
When did you get here?!
（スピーカー:伊織）
高次縫製師 いつの間に？
（縫）私は来たい所に来る
それは誰にも止められない
I go wherever I want to go,
and no one can stop me.
（スピーカー:皐月）何の用だ？
What do you want?
（縫）“何の用だ？”じゃないわよ
Don't get all, "What do you want?" with me.
It was Lady Ragyou.
羅暁様よ
She said she wanted to hear the
results of the Battlefield Trip in person.
襲学旅行の成果 直接聞きたいって
誰かさんから本能字学園に
出禁食らって暇だから—
And since I had time to kill because a certain
someone barred me from Honnouji Academy,
I came all the way to pick you up!
私がわざわざ迎えに来たの
フン どうせ鮮血と純潔の戦いでも
見に来たのだろう
I bet you just wanted to see
Senketsu and Junketsu square off.
（スピーカー:縫）
さすが 皐月様！
Bingo, Lady Satsuki!
私のこと理解してくれるのは
あなたしかいない
You're the only one who
truly understands me!
That's rich, coming from someone who
refuses to let anyone understand her.
（皐月）誰の理解も
拒んでいる者が よく言う
Well then, shall we make
our way to the mansion?
（縫）じゃ お屋敷に
行っちゃおうっか〜！
Iori.
（揃･伊織）わっ
（皐月）伊織 四天王に伝えろ
Pass on a message to the Four Devas:
"I'll be returning late.
私の戻りは遅れる
You must all remain vigilant
until you reach Honnouji Academy.
全員 本能字学園に着くまで
気を抜くな
Remember, the Battlefield Trip
isn't over until you get home."
帰宅するまでが襲学旅行だ
Yes, ma'am!
はい
Shall I pour you another
cup of tea in the meantime?
（揃）
もう１杯 お茶を召し上がる時間が
出来たようですね
Please.
（皐月）頼む
She got us.
（美木杉(みきすぎ)）してやられたな
（黄長瀬(きながせ)）だが命はある
But we still escaped with our lives.
As long as we're alive, we can fight.
（黄長瀬）生きていれば戦える
（美木杉）そのとおりだ
You're right.
Ryuuko, I'm amazed you fought
Kiryuuin Satsuki to a draw.
（美木杉）流子君 鬼龍院皐月と
引き分けるとは よく戦ったね
Well done.
Come.
来たまえ
Hey, Mikisugi!
（流子）おい美木杉 どこへ行く？
Where are you going?
Kiryuuin Satsuki hit the nail on the head.
（美木杉）
鬼龍院皐月の言うとおりだよ
The tides have turned.
状況は動いた
ここまで来たら隠し事は無意味だ
There is no reason to
keep secrets any longer.
It's time I exposed everything to you.
君に全てを見せるときが来た
What?!
（マコ）え〜！ あなたは—
...Were you really...
Mr. Mikisugi all along?!
美木杉先生だったんですか？
（美木杉）
そうか この姿は初めてか？
That's right.
You've never seen me like this before.
I never knew you were an exhibitionist!
美木杉先生
露出狂だったんですね
（美木杉）
ハハハ 僕たちはヌー…
...We are Nu—
You've found a comrade-in-arms, Ryuuko!
（マコ）流子ちゃんの仲間だね
（流子）一緒にすんな！
Don't lump us together!
フッ マコ 今回はお前は帰れ
Mako, you go home for now.
Huh?
Mankanshoku,
（美木杉）満艦飾(まんかんしょく)君
if you come with us, you will need to
hurl yourself into the maelstrom of battle.
ついてくると君も戦いの渦中に
身を投じることになる
Do you have that resolve?
その覚悟があるかい？
ありません！
I do not!
Figures.
だよな だったら帰れ
Go home, then.
I don't have the
resolve to go nude yet.
（マコ）私にはまだ
裸になる覚悟はありません
That's what you're talking about?!
そっち！
...But what I do have...
でも あたしにあるのは—
is the desire to be
Ryuuko's friend forever!
流子ちゃんと ずっとずっと
友達だという気持ちです
So I'll go with you!
だから ついてゆくのです！
...Mako...
マコ… フッ
Very well.
（美木杉）わかった！
Follow us!
ついてきたまえ
（マコ）はい！
（流子）え…
Okay!
Huh?
Woo!
（黄長瀬）とうっ
（水しぶきの音）
What?
（流子）
え… ちょ… マコ
...Hey—
（マコ）ほうっ
（水しぶきの音）
Hoo!
Mako!
...Hang on...
（流子）
え… ちょ… マコ
待てよ なんで飛び込み？
Why are you diving in?
Ryuuko.
流子君 ここが君が知るべき
真実の入り口だ
Beyond here lies the truth you must learn.
Let's go skinny dipping!
レッツ スキニー ダイビング！
Huh?
あれ？
What?
え〜 ちょっと！
Wait!
Take off Junketsu, please.
（鳳凰丸(ほうおうまる)）
純潔をお脱ぎください
こちらでお預かりします
We'll hold on to it for you.
The CEO left a message for you.
社長からのご伝言です
She wants you to wait for her
at the grand bathhouse.
大浴場でお待ちください
KIRYUUIN
RESIDENCE
GRAND
BATHHOUSE
You're pulling off that
Godrobe quite well,
（羅暁）よく着てはいるが—
but it would appear
you're pushing yourself.
無理もしているようだな
Mother.
（皐月）お母様
This herbal extract will increase
your affinity with Life Fibers.
（羅暁）この薬湯は
生命戦維との融和性を高める
Be sure to soak yourself well.
（羅暁）よく つかりなさい
（皐月）はい
I will.
（羅暁）良い肌だ
My, such nice skin you have.
Entrust your heart to me.
心を委ねなさい
（羅暁）みそぎを行う
（皐月）ハッ
I shall purify you.
Humans are such fragile beings.
（羅暁）人間とは
全く かよわいものだな
When we're naked like this,
（羅暁）
こうして裸になると
たまらなく不安になる
（皐月）
ハァ… ハッ… ハッ…
anxiety overcomes us.
It makes us want to hurry up and cover our
bodies in the wonders known as "clothes".
早くこの体を服という
すばらしい存在で覆いたくなる
That is our instinct.
それが—
本能だ
...And species that defy their instincts...
本能に逆らう種族は やがて—
（皐月）
ハァ ハッ…ああっ
...will eventually...
fall into ruin.
絶滅に至る
You can get out now.
（羅暁）上がりなさい
（皐月）ハッ
There is somewhere we need to be.
行くべき所がある
...Does that mean...
（皐月）では？
（羅暁）ああ
Yes.
You did well, Satsuki.
皐月もよく働いた
鬼龍院の一族として
As a Kiryuuin,
私の後継者として
and as my successor,
it is now time for you to
learn where all this began.
根源なるものを知るときが来た
（流子･マコ）プハ〜ッ
There was a place like this
underneath Osaka?
（流子）大阪の地下にこんな空洞が
It's in pretty bad shape, though.
（マコ）
でも ずいぶん壊れちゃってるね
Jakuzure sure did a number on us.
（美木杉）蛇崩に してやられたよ
だが これで全部ってわけじゃない
However, there is more to
this place than meets the eye.
Mikisugi! Kinagase!
（戦闘員）美木杉さん
（マコ）あれ？
（戦闘員）黄長瀬さん
I see this place was spared.
（美木杉）こっちは無事だったか
We were right to follow
your orders and take refuge here.
（戦闘員）
美木杉さんの指示どおり
避難しておいて正解でした
I guess being a worrywart
pays off from time to time.
心配性も役に立つってことだ
（流子）ふう〜ん
（美木杉）ん？
I see Nudist Beach has had
quite a bit of money poured into it.
ヌーディスト･ビーチってのも—
ずいぶんと金(かね)が
かかってるじゃねえか
It's all thanks to your father.
（美木杉）君のお父さんのおかげだ
（流子）父さんの？
Dad?
（美木杉）
大した科学者だったからね
彼の持っている特許で—
He was an amazing scientist.
Using the patents he held, he collected money
from corporations worldwide.
世界中の企業から
金をかき集めていたようだ
And with those funds,
he created this organization.
その資金でこの組織を
つくり上げた
（マコ）ん〜
（流子）じゃあ…
...Then...
Indeed!
そう！ ヌーディスト･ビーチを
つくったのは纏一身博士だ！
...Nudist Beach was founded...
by Dr. Matoi Isshin!
What?!
（女性たち）あ〜ん
（女性）
おじいちゃん かわいい
（一身）ウフフ…
（一身）ムヒョ〜！ フフフ…
（女性たち）キャー ウフフ…
I don't think it happened like that.
そういうんじゃないと思うぞ
えっ あ〜 なんでわかったの？
私の頭の中
How did you know what was
going through my mind?
（鮮血）
以心伝心になってきたな 流子
You two are on the same
wavelength now, huh, Ryuuko?
あんまりうれしくないな
I can't say I'm too happy about that.
Wow, Ryuuko!
すご〜い流子ちゃん
Now I've got a friend who's
both outside and inside my mind!
私の頭の中にも外にもいる
友達なんだね
...Er...
Clothes
Now, Ryuuko,
さて 流子君
この地球上で服を着る生物は
どれだけいると思う？
how many organisms on this planet
do you know of that wear clothes?
Just us humans, obviously.
（流子）そりゃ人間だけだろ
Correct.
（美木杉）そうだ
Out of the countless species on Earth,
この地球に数ある種の中で—
the only one to wear
clothes is Homo sapiens.
我々 ホモ･サピエンスだけが
服を着る
And why do you think that is?
それは なぜか？
It is not that only humans wear clothing,
人間だけが服を着るんじゃない
服を着た生物が人間になったんだ
but rather that the creatures who wore clothes
became mankind as we know it today!
Life Fibers caused Homo sapiens, previously
just one of many anthropoids, to evolve this far.
生命戦維が類人猿の１種族であった
ホモ･サピエンスを—
ここまで進化させた
そう 我々人類が
服に選ばれたのだよ
That's right.
In this case, the clothes made the mankind!
KIRYUUIN
RESIDENCE
FIBER
PALACE
FORBIDDEN
ROOM
This is where it all began?
（皐月）これが根源なるもの
Correct.
（羅暁）そう 全ての始まり
原初(げんしょ)生命戦維だ
The source of everything:
the original Life Fiber.
ORIGINAL
LIFE FIBER
宇宙を放浪する この光る糸玉が
地球に到達したとき—
The moment this shining ball of thread that had
wandered across space touched down on Earth,
人類は服に奉仕する存在と
なることを—
humans were fated to become
beings that served clothes.
宿命づけられた
Life Fibers will become clothes
and cover up the planet.
生命戦維は服となり
この星を覆い尽くす
They are COVERS,
それが“カバーズ”であり—
and nobody in this world
can oppose them.
この世界の誰も
逆らうことはできない
We, the Kiryuuin family,
我々 鬼龍院家は
彼らカバーズの意志の代弁者だ
are the mouthpiece for COVERS' will.
Do you understand that?
わかっているね？
Yes, Mother.
（皐月）はい お母様
Clothes made mankind?
（流子）
“服が人間を選んだ”だと？
What do you mean?
どういうことなんだ？
（マコ）わ〜お
Life Fibers are an
extraterrestrial lifeform!
（美木杉）生命戦維は
宇宙から来た生命体なんだ
Antiquity
They came to Earth in ancient times
and induced human evolution!
太古の地球にやって来て
人類の進化を促したのだ
What?!
Mako
Does that mean Senketsu's
an extraterrestrial being?
んじゃあ鮮血ちゃん
宇宙人なの？
He's not only a sailor uniform,
セーラー服なのにエ〜イリアン！
but also an alien?!
So that's how it is.
（鮮血）そういうことか
Don't just accept it!
（流子）
納得すんじゃねえ 何だそりゃ
訳わかんねえよ！
What the hell is that
supposed to mean?!
Could you pipe down and hear me out?
（美木杉）
黙って話を聞いてくれないか
今は順を追って説明するから
I'll explain it from the ground up.
Life Fibers are a
lifeform from outer space.
（美木杉）生命戦維は
宇宙から訪れた生命体だ
その星の生物に寄生し
その神経電流を食らって繁殖する
Like parasites, they use
native lifeforms as their hosts
and breed by feeding off
their nerve pulses.
However,
だが 直接体内に寄生すると—
when they directly inhabit a body,
they place too much strain on
the nervous system, destroying it.
その負荷に耐えきれず
神経が焼き切れてしまう
That is why they decided to cover
the creatures' bodies instead.
（美木杉）
だから彼らは生物の体を
覆うことにした
They can only obtain a miniscule amount
of energy from the skin's nerve endings,
（美木杉）
皮膚から得られる神経電流は
微量だが—
これなら寄生した生物を
殺すことはない
but this way,
they keep their hosts alive.
その時期に—
They chose the species with the furthest-developed
cerebrums at the time, Homo sapiens,
陸上でいちばん大脳が発達していた
ホモ･サピエンスを—
彼らは宿主に選び 進化を促した
to be their hosts and artificially
sped up their evolution.
And thus, mankind evolved.
人類は進化した
他の地球の生物とは
比べものにならないほど—
We developed brains that far
outclassed any other creature on Earth,
脳を発達させた
proliferated throughout the world,
そして人口を増やし
生態系の頂点に立った
and climbed to the
apex of the food chain.
だが それは生命戦維によって
導かれた かりそめの頂点だ
However, this was all
under the Life Fibers' guidance.
It is but a transient peak.
Ultimately, we humans are
just food for the Life Fibers.
（黄長瀬）俺たち人間は—
ヤツら生命戦維の餌だってことだ
（鮮血）そんな！
It can't be!
...Have I been feeding off Ryuuko—
じゃあ私も流子を…
Calm down, Senketsu.
（鮮血）んぐ…
（流子）落ち着け鮮血
We haven't heard the whole story yet.
まだ話は終わってねえ
だったら なんで全部の服に
生命戦維が入ってねえ？
Why don't all clothes have
Life Fibers in them, then?
Right now, most of us wear clothes
normally and lead normal lives.
あたしら人間は普通に服を着て
普通に生活してる
Honnouji Academy students are pretty much
the only ones who wear such strange outfits!
おかしな服を着てるのは
本能字学園の連中くらいだろ？
You're right.
（美木杉）確かに君の言うとおりだ
（美木杉）
人類の進化を促した生命戦維は—
The only possible conclusion is that,
having induced mankind's evolution,
the Life Fibers left us with only
the habit of clothing ourselves
人類に服を着る
習慣だけを残して—
and entered a long period of dormancy.
長い沈黙に入ったとしか
考えられない
It was around twenty years ago that
they came out of their dormant state.
彼らが沈黙を破ったのは
20年ほど前だ
Kiryuuin Ragyou made contact
with the original Life Fiber,
鬼龍院羅暁が
原初生命戦維と接触し—
彼らは再び目覚めた
そう纏博士から聞いている
which led to their reawakening.
Or so I heard from Dr. Matoi.
They were waiting
for the opportune time.
取り入れの時期を待ってたんだよ
Don't people wait until cattle
are nice and plump, too?
人間だって家畜が育つまで
待つだろうが
...Was I...
（鮮血）私は流子が育つのを
待っていたのか？
waiting for Ryuuko to grow up?
Is that why I need her blood?!
流子の血が必要なのは
そういうことなのか？
だから落ち着けって
鮮血はそんなんじゃねえ！
Like I said, calm down!
You're not like that, Senketsu!
混乱してるのか？ 鮮血は
Is Senketsu panicking?
...If so, tell him...
だったら伝えてくれ
that the two of you represent our hope.
流子君と鮮血は我々の希望だ
Hope?
（流子）希望？
（美木杉）そうだ
That's right.
（美木杉）その神衣鮮血は
生命戦維と戦うために—
Godrobe Senketsu was created by
Dr. Matoi to fight against the Life Fibers.
纏博士が人工的に
作り上げたものなんだ
And you're the only one
そして その神衣を
着こなせるのは—
who can pull off that Godrobe, Ryuuko!
（美木杉）流子君しかいない
（鮮血）ううっ
I'm the only one?
私しか… でも なぜ？
But why?
You are extraordinarily
resistant to Life Fibers.
（美木杉）君は生命戦維に
非常に強い耐性がある
恐らく纏博士はそれを知っていた
Dr. Matoi probably knew that.
That is why he crafted
...Senketsu to suit you—
だから君用に
その鮮血を作ったんだ
鬼龍院の野望を止めるために
to put an end to the
Kiryuuins' ambitions!
The Doctor once researched Life Fibers
under orders from Kiryuuin Ragyou.
博士は もともと—
鬼龍院羅暁の命で
生命戦維を研究していたのだ
But once he learned the
terrifying truth, he fled from her
だが その恐ろしさを知って—
彼女のもとを逃げ出して
ひそかに対抗組織をつくった
and secretly formed
a counter-organization.
それが—
...That is...
who we are: Nudist Beach!
我々 ヌーディスト･ビーチだ
I see.
（鮮血）そうか… 纏博士が私を…
So that is why Dr. Matoi created me.
Yes.
I remember it now.
（鮮血）確かにそうだ
I was born in that
underground laboratory,
あの地下室で私は生まれた
but I was immediately put to sleep.
だが すぐに眠らされた
半年後 流子が訪れるまで ずっと
Until Ryuuko came to me,
six months later.
I'm sorry for keeping
all this a secret until now.
（美木杉）ここまで
黙っていたのは悪かった
But the Kiryuuins' might
knows no bounds.
だが 鬼龍院の力は強い
君が鮮血の力を自由に
引き出せるようになるまでは—
Until you got to the point where you
could freely call upon Senketsu's powers,
I couldn't tell you the whole story.
全てを話すことはできなかったんだ
あたしが生命戦維の力に
のみ込まれたら—
Yeah, you even planned on eliminating me
そのときは容赦なく
始末しようとしてたしな
if I were ever consumed
by the Life Fibers.
ああ そうだ
今でも そのつもりだよ
Exactly.
That plan hasn't changed.
Tsumugu!
...Yeah, this story...
確かに こんな話—
is a bit hard to believe.
そう簡単には信じられねえな
But it is the truth.
これが真実だ
The clothes produced by REVOCS,
the company Kiryuuin Ragyou leads,
（美木杉）
鬼龍院羅暁が社長を務める
ＲＥＶＯＣＳ(リボックス)社の服は—
世界中のほとんどの国で
着られている
are worn more or less across the globe.
Each one of those outfits
contains Life Fibers.
その服の全てに生命戦維が
織り込まれている
At the moment, they still lie dormant,
今はまだ活動を停止しているが—
Hououmaru Rei
but if they ever were to awaken,
それらの服が目覚めたとき
何が起こるか予想もつかない
Harime Nui
Kiryuuin
Satsuki
Ragyou
there's no telling what will happen.
But one thing is for sure:
ただ それが人類にとって—
they will be a massive threat to mankind.
大いなる脅威になるということは
間違いない
So you succeeded in taking over all the schools
in the country and suppressing Nudist Beach?
（羅暁）
全国学園支配と—
ヌーディスト･ビーチの
鎮圧は成功したね？
（皐月）はい
Yes.
That means we can advance the
Honnouji Academy experiment to the next stage.
（羅暁）
本能字学園実験都市も
次の段階に進められるな
We've also completed construction
of the Ragyou Stadium.
（鳳凰丸）
既にラギョウ･スタジアムも
完成しております
The festival is all set to go.
祝祭の準備は整いました
Very well.
（羅暁）
いいだろう　計画も最終段階だ
Let us move to the
final stage of the plan:
the Great Culture and Sports Festival.
大文化体育祭を実施しなさい
As you wish.
（皐月）はい
What will you do?
（羅暁）お前はどうする？
I haven't been home in a while,
（皐月）久しぶりの自宅です
今日は泊まっていきます
so I'll stay the night.
Is that so?
そうか 黒井戸(くろいど) よろしく頼む
Take care of her needs, Kuroido.
Honnouji Academy is your creation.
お前がつくった本能字学園
どれほどのものか
楽しみにしているよ
I'm looking forward to
seeing just what it's made of.
We shall welcome you
with open arms, Mother.
歓迎します お母様
（流子）な〜るほどな〜
（マコ）うっ？
Now I get it.
So you're telling Senketsu and I to fight
hand-in-hand for the sake of mankind, huh?
（流子）
私と鮮血 手に手を取って—
人類の平和のために
戦えってことか〜
ああ〜 もう！
To hell with that!
ふざけんな！
Ryuuko?
流子君
You mean to say
Senketsu's just a weapon?
だったら鮮血はただの兵器か？
戦うために作られた戦闘服か？
A combat outfit
made purely for battle?
You've gotta be kidding me.
冗談じゃねえ こいつには
こいつの意志があるんだ
He's got a mind of his own!
Now you're telling me
he was born to kill his brethren?
仲間殺しのために生まれたなんて
I feel so damn sorry for him!
それじゃ鮮血が
あんまりかわいそうじゃねえか！
What are you doing?
（美木杉）な… 何をする！
（マコ）え？
（流子）えいっ
This is Nudist Beach, right?
ヌーディスト･ビーチだろ！
What's wrong with me stripping off?
裸になって何が悪い？
...Ryuuko...
（鮮血）流子
I can't fight while wearing you!
（流子）
あたしはお前を着ては戦えない
お前が戦う必要もない！
You don't need to fight either!
Let me tell you two
useful pieces of information.
（黄長瀬）
２つ いいことを教えてやろう
One: there's no reason for a
Godrobe that doesn't fight to exist.
１つ 戦わない神衣に
存在価値はない
Two: I won't hesitate to
dispose of any such Godrobes.
２つ なら俺は
今すぐそいつを始末する
You'll have to do it over my dead body.
やるなら私をやってからにしな
Fine by me.
上等だ その望み かなえてやろう
I'll grant that wish of yours.
わわわ… みんな怖いよ怖いよ
You're all scaring me!
This is bad!
まずい まずいね
ここはお菓子食べて落ち着こう
Why don't we have
some snacks and calm down?
Let's see.
どれどれ お土産を拝借
I'll borrow some souvenirs.
まずいよ〜
This sucks!
This whole thing sucks!
このお菓子も まずいよ〜
kurikaesu mainichi ga
My monotonous everyday life
totsuzen iro wo kaeru
Took on a new hue
sonna koto dokka nozonde itanda kedo ne
A part of me always wished for that to happen
iza to naru to
But when it actually did
okubyoumono deshita
I was too scared to act
himitsu ne
That's a secret, okay?
hitori furuete
Trembling alone
soshite kimi ni aitakute
I miss you so much
zutto mikata da yo nante ieta nara
If only I could tell you that I'll always be on your side
muteki
We could be invincible
sou sa tobitatsu toki wa futari de
When we take flight, we'll do so together
tachimukai
We'll make a stand
kakaekirenai okubyou ni
I want to keep smiling
tsuppattatte waratte itai
Even when my cowardice freezes me in place
hitori kiri zutsu ga awasatte
Every little thing will come together
ookina chikara ni naru yo
To give us great strength
ima nee kanjita
That's how I feel right now
NEXT EPISODE PREVIEW
（鮮血）
父の願いを知る流子
Ryuuko has found out
about her father's desire.
迷うな流子 私とお前は
着つつ 着られつ
Don't hesitate, Ryuuko.
YOU AND I
You and I don't wear on each other.
大文化体育祭
それは鬼龍院の勝利宣言
The Great Culture and Sports Festival!
THE GREAT CULTURE
AND
SPORTS FESTIVAL
It's the Kiryuuins' declaration of victory.
DECLARATION OF VICTORY
Only we can stop them.
止められるのは我々だけだ
ONLY WE
次回 キルラキル
「何故にお前は」
Next time on KILL la KILL,
"Tell Me Why".
EPISODE 17
TELL ME WHY